<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-12-11T23:40:02+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/group19//</id><title type="html">Mentor Matching - Team 19</title><subtitle>Matthew Bell, Christopher Lau and Harry Chen are working on creating a system to match mentors and mentees in their workplace based on their preferences, on behalf of Atos UK. 
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Plan for term 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/management/2016/12/10/term-2-plan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plan for term 2" /><published>2016-12-10T23:30:51+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-10T23:30:51+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/management/2016/12/10/term-2-plan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/management/2016/12/10/term-2-plan.html">&lt;p&gt;This page details the project plans for term 2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a finalized set of requirements along with completed designed of our architecture and matching algorithm, our next goal for the second term is to develop our application based on the specified requirements and constraints. We will be developing functionalities and features in the order we prioritized in our MoSCoW requirements. We will also be implementing the user interface based on the first prototype we have created. We will also be splitting roles on team members who will be responsible for developing the frontend and backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, we will continue to use the SCRUM agile development process to manage the process with weekly sprints to ensure that progress is on track. We will also have regular meetings with our client to show our progress in different stages of development and take into account their feedback. We might also be planning on preparing short user acceptance tests before every client meeting, so that all new features we develop during a sprint go through a formal approval process.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">This page details the project plans for term 2</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bi-Weekly Reports and Meeting Minutes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/management/2016/12/07/biweekly-reports.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bi-Weekly Reports and Meeting Minutes" /><published>2016-12-07T23:30:51+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-07T23:30:51+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/management/2016/12/07/biweekly-reports</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/management/2016/12/07/biweekly-reports.html">&lt;p&gt;This page contains reports which are produced fortnightly by the team which record the progress of the project. It also contains the meeting minutes for the meetings we have conducted so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot;&gt;Bi-Weekly Reports&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains all bi-weekly reports of term 1 to date. Click to download a pdf version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mbellgb/syseng19-docs/raw/master/biweekly-reports/2016-10-12.pdf&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;Week 1 and 2 (October 12)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mbellgb/syseng19-docs/raw/master/biweekly-reports/2016-10-28.pdf&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;Week 3 and 4 (October 28)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mbellgb/syseng19-docs/raw/master/biweekly-reports/2016-11-18.pdf&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;Week 5 and 6 (November 18)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mbellgb/syseng19-docs/raw/master/biweekly-reports/2016-12-02.pdf&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;Week 7 and 8 (December 2)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot;&gt;Meeting Minutes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section contains all meeting minutes for the meetings we conducted to date. Click to download a pdf version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mbellgb/syseng19-docs/raw/master/meeting%20minutes/meeting%201.pdf&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;Meeting 1 (Initial Client Meeting)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mbellgb/syseng19-docs/raw/master/meeting%20minutes/meeting%202.pdf&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;Meeting 2 (CTO meeting)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mbellgb/syseng19-docs/raw/master/meeting%20minutes/meeting%203.pdf&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;Meeting 3 (Supervisor Meeting)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mbellgb/syseng19-docs/raw/master/meeting%20minutes/meeting%204.pdf&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;Meeting 4 (Client meeting 2)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">This page contains reports which are produced fortnightly by the team which record the progress of the project. It also contains the meeting minutes for the meetings we have conducted so far.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Project Management Tools</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/management/2016/12/07/collborative.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project Management Tools" /><published>2016-12-07T23:30:51+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-07T23:30:51+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/management/2016/12/07/collborative</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/management/2016/12/07/collborative.html">&lt;p&gt;This page includes all of the tools we have used to manage our project. This includes communication, documentation, prototype design and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot;&gt;Facebook Messenger&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During our first meeting we set up a facebook group for communication between each other and share our ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trello is a collabration tool that organizes our projects on several boards. In our team we divided boards into three parts: Backlog, In progress and Completed. We create tasks by making boards and then add it into the Backlog section, for every task we assign a due date, members responsible for that task and add labels on it to indicate urgency. Once we start working on a task the card would be moved into the in progress section. The team agreed to take a maximum of 6 tasks in progress every week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Github is a version-control service based on git. Our team built three github repositories: one for documentation, main code repository, one repository for the project website. Through github each team member could work separately on same project simultaneously by making branches of master branch and send pull requst to merge each one’s work. Also the version control through github could help us to review our work thus find problems in previous work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot;&gt;Google Drive and Google Docs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the documentation we have completed so far (which includes bi-weekly reports, research, design) are shared in google drive before converting it into Latex for submission or adding the content to the project website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">This page includes all of the tools we have used to manage our project. This includes communication, documentation, prototype design and others.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Testing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/12/07/testing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Testing" /><published>2016-12-07T23:30:51+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-07T23:30:51+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/12/07/testing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/12/07/testing.html">&lt;p&gt;This page details the testing stratedies we plan to execute for the project. This is to ensure that our system meets the specified requirements and quality standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot; id=&quot;initial-sketch&quot;&gt;Unit Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure the integrity, completeness and correctness of our software, we plan to develop a series of individual test cases which consists of unit tests for both our front and back-ends. After developing a feature we plan to carry out testing by running the test cases to ensure no new bugs are introduced. Since we are using django for our backend, we plan to use the &lt;strong&gt;unittest&lt;/strong&gt; module built in to the standard library. Django also provides an API and tools for integration. As for the front end we plan to use an Angular testing tool called &lt;strong&gt;Jasmine&lt;/strong&gt;. Jasmine provides functions that help structure our tests and also make assertions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test our matching algortihm, we plan to use an open-source tool called &lt;strong&gt;Appium&lt;/strong&gt;. Appium is useful for automaing native,mobile web and also hybrid applications. Since Appium is “cross-platform” we can write test cases against multiple platforms using the same API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot; id=&quot;initial-sketch&quot;&gt;Functional Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Functional testing is used as a quality assurance process for a software system. It refers to activities that verify a specific action or function of the code. Functional testing tends to ensure that a particular function and feature works.
In order to carry out functional testing, we plan to use our requirement specification to construct a series of test cases and use them for manual black-box testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot; id=&quot;initial-sketch&quot;&gt;Compatibility Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our client mentioned that the final system must be able to run on different types of operating systems and web browsers. Hence it is important that we ensure the compatibility of our application. Below are some of the test we plan to carry out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Browser compatibility&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is to ensure that the application works on the most widely used browsers. Application may behave differently when run on different browsers. Different browsers may also have different configurations and settings that a web page should be compatible with. Therefore we plan to test our application on popular browsers such as Chrome, Internet Explorer, Firefox, Safari and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;OS compatibility&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In some cases a functionality of a web application may not be compatible in all oprating systems. Our client mentioned that the application ust be able to run on mobile devices as well which include the Android OS and IOS. We therefore plan to test our aplication on mobile operating systems as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot; id=&quot;initial-sketch&quot;&gt;User Acceptance Test (UAT)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would be the last phase of testing that we plan to execute. We might also be conducting regular UAT during meetings with our client if we have completed certain functionalities and features. In order to carry out UAT, we plan to design tesst cases which cover our key requirements. We will then present these test cases to the client who might pass them on to the potential users of the system. We plan to use the feedback received by our client to improve overall quality of the system. This process is to ensure that the system can handle required tasks in the real-world scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">This page details the testing stratedies we plan to execute for the project. This is to ensure that our system meets the specified requirements and quality standards.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">User Interface Development</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/12/04/user-interface.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="User Interface Development" /><published>2016-12-04T23:30:51+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-04T23:30:51+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/12/04/user-interface</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/12/04/user-interface.html">&lt;p&gt;This page highlights the design and development of the user interface and user experience of the front end system. This includes initial sketches, wireframes and also first prototype of our application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#initial-sketch&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: 7px;&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;Initial sketches&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#wireframes&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: 7px;&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;Initial Wireframes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#hci-principles&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: 7px;&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;HCI Principles&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#first-prototype&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: 7px;&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;First prototype&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot; id=&quot;initial-sketch&quot;&gt;Initial sketches&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the beginning stages of developing the user interface, we sketched out some ideas on how the various screens/pages/views will look layout-wise. We decided that the system will have 6 main pages, 1 for user authentication, a clean and user friendly home page, and also 4 other pages for the application process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/first-sketch.JPG&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;first sketch&quot; height=&quot;55%&quot; width=&quot;60%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;^ Back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot; id=&quot;wireframes&quot;&gt;Initial Wireframes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After sketching out how we think the layout of the different views should be, we proceeded to produce the first wireframe; creating cleaner and clearer overviews of the layouts. The wireframes were designed using Ionic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 5 main layouts for the wireframe. The first is the user authentication pages where users create an account to use the application. The second page is the landing page which is where users can choose to enrol in any of the available mentorship programs. When the user selects a mentorship program, there would be a page that shows the details and information of that specific program. After that the user will have to enter their respective interests so that the system can match them to a mentor or mentee. Users can also manually enter some of their interests if it is not available in the selection. Finally the process of application is the confirmation page, where users choose to register themselves as a mentor or mentee. &lt;strong&gt;(Please click to enlarge images)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;image-pop-up&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/signup.png&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;first sketch&quot; height=&quot;30%&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Authentication page&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;image-pop-up&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/home.png&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;first sketch&quot; height=&quot;30%&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Landing page&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;image-pop-up&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/overview.png&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;first sketch&quot; height=&quot;30%&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Overview of mentorship program&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;image-pop-up&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/interest.png&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;first sketch&quot; height=&quot;30%&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Application page(Entering interests)&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-4&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;image-pop-up&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/confirmation.png&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;first sketch&quot; height=&quot;30%&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Confirmation page&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;^ Back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot; id=&quot;hci-principles&quot;&gt;HCI Principles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While designing the UI, we focused on anticipating the needs of our user and ensuring that the interface has elements that are easy to access, understand and use to facilitate those actions. While choosing elements to use within our interface, we tried to be as consistent and as possible to acheive a UI that supports efficiency, task completion and user satisfaction. The ways that we were able to acheive this were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Visibility&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In order to acheive visibility, we made sure that elements were lay out in a manner that makes it obvious what they are used for. We tried to keep elements in large sections and also position important information at a center location. We also try to arrange elements in an orderly row and column system. Icons were also used to help express specific functionalities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Feedback&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is when the users presses a button and the system reacts in a manner that clearly communicates what has just been accomplished. In order to acheive this, we used functionalities such as hovers on buttons and links and pop ups. We also try to incorporate as much transtition when switching from different pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Consistency&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The main way in which we were able to achieve consistency in our UI, was by making sure that all our structures and elements were consistent. We tried to make sure that every page followed the same general theme. For example, colour themes and font styles and sizes would be maintained throughout the individal pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;^ Back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot; id=&quot;first-prototype&quot;&gt;First Prototype&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to create the first prototype of the user interface. This prototype builds on what we have got from the wireframes, adding links between the different views and responsive elements such as drop-down menus and tick-boxes to demonstrate how those elements work. However, this prototype does not aim to represent the visual design of the UI. A link to the interactive Ionic prototype is available below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://creator.ionic.io/share/23059853fc12&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: 7px;&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-info btn-lg&quot;&gt;First prototype&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Modal for images --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;modal fade&quot; id=&quot;imagemodal&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; role=&quot;dialog&quot; aria-labelledby=&quot;myModalLabel&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;modal-dialog&quot;&gt;
    	&lt;div class=&quot;modal-content&quot;&gt;              
      		&lt;div class=&quot;modal-body&quot;&gt;
      			&lt;button type=&quot;button&quot; class=&quot;close&quot; data-dismiss=&quot;modal&quot;&gt;&lt;span aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&amp;times;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr-only&quot;&gt;Close&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
        		&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;imagepreview&quot; style=&quot;width: 90%; height: 60%;&quot; /&gt;
      			&lt;/div&gt;
    	&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- Pop up for images --&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
	$(function() {
		$('.image-pop-up').on('click', function() {
			$('.imagepreview').attr('src', $(this).find('img').attr('src'));
			$('#imagemodal').modal('show');   
		});		
	});
&lt;/script&gt;</content><summary type="html">This page highlights the design and development of the user interface and user experience of the front end system. This includes initial sketches, wireframes and also first prototype of our application.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Architecture Research and Algorithm Design</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/12/02/architecture-designs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Architecture Research and Algorithm Design " /><published>2016-12-02T23:30:51+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-02T23:30:51+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/12/02/architecture-designs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/12/02/architecture-designs.html">&lt;p&gt;This page details the research we have done through the course of designing the architecture for our system. It also includes details of the design of our matching algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#important-decision&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: 7px;&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;Important Decisions&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#algorithm-design&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: 7px;&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;Algorithm Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot; id=&quot;important-decision&quot;&gt;Important Decisions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section highlights the decisions we have made as a team for future development of this project. These decisions include the technology and tools used to build the final system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table-responsive&quot;&gt;
	&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered decisionTable&quot;&gt;
		&lt;tbody&gt;
			&lt;col width=&quot;15%&quot; /&gt;
  			&lt;col width=&quot;85%&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td width=&quot;100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decision 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Which web application framework do we use for the &lt;strong&gt;front-end?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option Considered&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Angular JS and Ionic&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;	
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;React JS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ember JS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Decision&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Angular JS and Ionic&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;
					&lt;strong&gt;Why not React JS?&lt;/strong&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;We considered React JS due to its ability to build components and functionality which are well maintained. React is also able to render on server side which makes integration with backend easier. However, React is not a full framework as there are no router nor model management libraries built into ReactJS. Hence writing components is not as easy.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;strong&gt;Why not Ember JS&lt;/strong&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;We chose Ember JS as it is a flexible framework which speeds up the performance of our application without reloading the whole page. Ember is also good for REST API querying which is what we plan to use for communication with database. However, we have to write our own ajax requests since a lot of ember addons are ports of existing jQuery libraries and very few are written from scartch.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;strong&gt;Why Angular JS and Ionic&lt;/strong&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;The main advantages of Angular is the flexibility and support by the community. Angular JS is supported by Google and has a great development community. It also operates directly on DOM rather than inner HTML more efficiently. Our Client also heavily emphasised that the application should be available on mobile. Ionic is able to produce applications that can run on both IOS and Android environment. It also makes developing with Angular easier because modules from Angular ca be used.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;/tbody&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table-responsive&quot;&gt;
	&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered decisionTable&quot;&gt;
		&lt;tbody&gt;
			&lt;col width=&quot;15%&quot; /&gt;
  			&lt;col width=&quot;85%&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td width=&quot;100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decision 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Which web application framework do we use for the &lt;strong&gt;back-end?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td rowspan=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option Considered&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Django&lt;/td&gt;	
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ruby On Rails&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Node JS&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Revel&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Decision&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Django&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;
					&lt;strong&gt;Why not Ruby on Rails?&lt;/strong&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;We considered Ruby on Rails as one of our options due to the expressive nature of the ruby language, allowing funtions to be written very fast. Ruby also had a large developer following and library. However, due to scaffolding could mean that ou application is inflexible and also the dynamic nature of Ruby meant that it runs a little slower compares to statically typed languages.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;strong&gt;Why not Revel&lt;/strong&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;Revel was also an option due to its similarity to Ruby on Rails. Revel was written using the Go language which is statically and strongly typed language. Go has strong concurrency and has many multithreading features. However, Revel may not be the most suitable framework due to being too lightweight. This meant that we had to implement a lot features ourselves, making development inefficient.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;strong&gt;Deciding between Node JS and Django.&lt;/strong&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;After some discussion the team agreed that Node JS and Django was the most suitable for this application. However, we it was hard to decide between the two frameworks. Node JS is extremely popular over the last cople of years since the community is large and there is easily to find resources Node JS also shares a common language with web page scripts as Node JS programs are written in Javascript. Node applications are also Event-driven which means it can perform other tasks while wating for asynchronous operations.&lt;br /&gt;
					On the other hand, Django is a very high level framework written in python which could lead to rapid development. Django takes care of most aspects of web development such as user authentication and also has an in built admin system. The scalabitlity of Django also makes it very suitable for our application since there are a reasonable amount of users that could potentially use this application.&lt;br /&gt;
					Ultimately, the team decided on Django as the framework for the backend as we felt that Django had many in built systems that could be useful to our application, making development the most efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;/tbody&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;^ Back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot; id=&quot;algorithm-design&quot;&gt;Algorithm Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Input&lt;/strong&gt;: The algorithm will accept  two lists, Mentors and Mentees, containing users. Users have a name, as well as a list of tags.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Final Output&lt;/strong&gt;: A list of matches between mentors and mentees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Stage 1: Ranking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The algorithm will iterate through each mentee in turn: It will look at each mentor, and assign a ‘score’ between the mentee and mentor, which begins at 0. For each matching tag, the score should be increased by 10. Next, it should consider the constraints of the current mentorship programme. For each match in the mentorship programme (e.g., preferences on time served in company), the score should be increased by 5. If the match should absolutely not happen for whatever reason, the score should be set to 0 and the matching algorithm should move onto the next mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of this process, for each mentee, there should be a list of mentors and their scores. These should be sorted by the highest score first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we make this faster? Potentially we could cache some of the scores to adapt to similar matches, but for now it’s better to just write a brute force approach and optimise later if need be. To begin with, we should allow users to input tags for themselves. In the future though, we could use semantic analysis to find these tags automatically from their user bio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stage 2: Selecting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Each mentee then will be presented with their top three mentors. They will be invited to sort these according to preference (within a time limit), and once these have all been completed, the next stage will begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How will we implement this in reality? Most likely, we’ll use the first three values from each mentee’s matches/scores array and sort them in place to save memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stage 3: Matching&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The algorithm will now implement a version of the Gale-Shapley Algorithm to find an optimal set of matches given the mentee’s preferences. The difference here is that there is most likely an uneven amount of mentees to mentors. It’s worth noting at this point that mentors may be after more than one mentee; in this case, the score arrays need to be adjusted so that a mentor with x spaces has x values in the arrays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this algorithm is run, the matches are then sent to the DB to be saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Pseudocode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Below is the pseuodocode lllustrating the the 3 stages explained above. A user class is used to store the ID of the mentee or mentor, along with the required tags needed for matching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/pseuodocode.JPG&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;node.js&quot; height=&quot;80%&quot; width=&quot;95%&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;^ Back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">This page details the research we have done through the course of designing the architecture for our system. It also includes details of the design of our matching algorithm.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Technical Research</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/11/19/technical-research.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Technical Research" /><published>2016-11-19T23:30:51+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-19T23:30:51+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/11/19/technical-research</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/11/19/technical-research.html">&lt;p&gt;This page details all the technical research we have done (excluding architecture) throughout this project, including open-source libraries and frameworks that could be useful for the final system. Our research was split in to 2 categories which was frontend research and backend research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#back-end&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: 7px;&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;1. Backend Frameworks/Libraries&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#front-end&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: 7px;&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;2. Frontend Frameworks/Libraries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;back-end&quot; class=&quot;section-header&quot;&gt;Backend Frameworks/Libraries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!-- Node.js --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/node.jpg&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;node.js&quot; height=&quot;120&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Node.JS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Node.JS is an application framework that runs JavaScript code as a native app on computers. It’s gained extreme popularity over the last couple of years and I myself have used it for a few projects in the past. The community is rather large and there’s a library for pretty much anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Node.JS programs are written using JavaScript, a dynamic, untyped language developed originally for scripting web pages in the browser. Recent versions of the language have introduced classes and other useful features, but it’s type inferencing has some weird side effects &lt;code&gt;(try {} == [] and [] == {})&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Advantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Large developer community with plenty of libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy to write and deploy code.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shares a common language with web page scripts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Object variables - JavaScript internally uses hashes/dictionaries/key-value pairs to represent objects, and the value can be of any type… even functions. Makes for very quick development.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Event-driven - your Node app can do other things while waiting for asynchronous operations (disk I/O, http requests, etc) which can make up for only having one thread.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Single threaded - no concurrency features.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Callbacks - a comment paradigm of JavaScript is using callbacks: functions that accept another function which is called once the original function completes. It can often lead to very messy code, with five or six functions nested inside each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- Ruby on Rails --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/ruby.jpg&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;node.js&quot; height=&quot;120&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Ruby On Rails&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Ruby on Rails is a web framework that’s written in Ruby, a dynamic programming language. It relies heavily on scaffolding, and the directory/fire structure is rather rigid. However, it means that applications are developed very quickly, and is often used as a prototyping framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ruby language is extremely expressive, allowing functions to be written relatively fast without worrying too much about low level features like memory management. Also, like with Node.JS, Ruby has a large developer following and library, using the Rubygems service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Advantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fast development time thanks to a readable, dynamic language. Ruby trades off some processing overhead in lieu of developer satisfaction.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rails uses scaffold code to generate projects very quickly, and tasks like page routing, templating and database ORM (object relation model, where a row in a database table is represented with a language’s class) are built in.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruby contains symbols that can be used instead of strings for hash keys. For instance, &lt;code&gt;:id&lt;/code&gt; could represent the id of a user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scaffolding can mean that the project structure is inflexible, and code should be distributed between files as the Rails developers intended.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruby’s dynamic nature can mean that it runs a little slower than compiled/statically typed languages, as there’s overhead resulting from Ruby’s type inference engine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/django.jpg&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;node.js&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Django&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Django is a high level web framework that is written in python  that encourages rapid development. Django is also free and open source and is built by experienced developers which takes care of much hassle of certain parts of web development. One of the main advantages of Django is that it is really fast and is designed to help developers take applications from concept to completion very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Advantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very fast - Most of the aspects of web development are taken care of by the framework itself such as user authentication and form handling. It also has an inbuilt User Model implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Security - Django’s inbuilt user authentication system are reassuringly secure which helps developers avoid security mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scalability - Despite many in built system takes makes development really fast, Django is exceedingly scalable and flexible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maintainability - Since Django runs on python, it needs to maintain backwards compatibility when there are newer versions of python which makes it evolve slowly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Templating - Most inbuilt features in Django require the use of templates, which can be rigid to the developer when trying to implement something different.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/revel.jpg&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;node.js&quot; height=&quot;60&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Revel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Revel is a web framework written using the Go language, a statically and strongly typed language. Go’s main benefits are its strong concurrency and networking features, and is high level enough to hide things like memory management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Revel framework is similar to Ruby on Rails in that it employs the MVC (model, view, controller) design pattern to structure the project. It can be used for serving HTML from templates, or it can be also used for serving a RESTful JSON API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Advantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statically and strongly typed - the Go language may not have the syntactic sugar of Ruby or Python, but it’s built to run fast.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multithreading - Go uses channels to handle concurrent features, which can be used to create more optimised servers, if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Barebones - as Revel is very lightweight, it also means that the developer needs to implement a lot of features themselves, increasing development time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Revel uses scaffolding to generate the project files, which may mean that the project structure is rigid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;^ Back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;front-end&quot; class=&quot;section-header&quot;&gt;Frontend Frameworks/Libraries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!-- Angular --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/angularjs.jpg&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;node.js&quot; height=&quot;120&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;AngularJS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
AngularJS is an open-sourced Javascript framework used for developing single-page web application. It aims to overcome the shortages of HTML for building web application.AngularJS is much closer to model-view-view model pattern. Where model is the data in application, view is what shows to user, view-model provides functions and specific data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Advantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AngularJS is supported by Google and a great development community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AngularJS operate directly on DOM rather than inner HTML, more efficiently.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No need to use observable functions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extended features such as dependency injection, routing, animations, view orchestration, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Source code too complex.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not easy to learn how to write your own directive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/ionic.jpg&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;node.js&quot; height=&quot;70&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Ionic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Since one of the requirements of our application was being mobile compatible, we decided to look into Ionic Framework as well. Ionic is a HTML5 SDK (software development kit) used to build hybrid mobile app by using Html, Css and Javascript. By using Ionic Creator, we could build a similar user interface interactions like native mobile app. Ionic is based on AngularJS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Advantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support cordova plugins to enrich functions in our app.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once produce ionic program it could be run on both IOS and Android development.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Powerful CLI tool: Control and manage you project easier.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Providing beautiful  UI components.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developing using AngularJS, can use all the modules from angular.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not equal to native app, native device’s API depends on whether Cordova support it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can not deal with huge amount of images.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some platforms like windows phone are not supported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/bootstrap.jpg&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;node.js&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; width=&quot;160&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Bootstrap includes CSS, HTML and JavaScript components. It adheres to responsive web design standards, allowing developers to create responsive sites of all complexities and sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Advantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Responsive web design support (can also be disabled if required)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Excellent documentation available online&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updated continously, hence it includes the latest and best features. It is also upgraded to use Sass as a CSS processor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Out-of-the-box file size of 276kB due to excessive number of rarely used styles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Excessive number of HTML classes and DOM elements can be messy and confusing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/reactjs.jpg&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;node.js&quot; height=&quot;70&quot; width=&quot;170&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;React&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
React.js is a JavaScript library for building user interfaces, built by top engineers at Facebook. React is all about reusable components. However, unlike frameworks, which are built with the goal of getting whole apps up and running quickly, the only thing you do with React is build components. As React.js’s core functionality, components make reusing code, testing, and separating concerns easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Advantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy to know how a component is rendered, you just look at the render function.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;React is able to render on server side.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;React ensures readability and makes maintainability easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s not a full framework. There’s no router nor model management libraries built into reactJS – unlike angular or ember. Hence one needs to have some degree of experience in picking libraries to fulfill these needs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;React is rather verbose. Writing components isn’t as straight forward as pure HTML &amp;amp; JS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2016/group19/assets/img/emberjs.jpg&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;node.js&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; width=&quot;160&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Ember.Js&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Ember.js is an open source JavaScript client-side framework for developing the web applications and uses the MVC(Model-View-Controller) architecture pattern. Ember.js is mainly used to creating reusable and maintainable JavaScript web applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Advantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ember.js is an open source JavaScript framework under (MIT license).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is a flexible framework that embraces the concept of fast web page. It allows to speed up the performance of your application without reloading the whole page.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It has the handlebars templating library which is similar as HTML and also embed an expressions that changes the display.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very dependant on jQuery libraries. Very few libraries are written from scratch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Less space for customization of everything.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No server-side rendering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;^ Back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">This page details all the technical research we have done (excluding architecture) throughout this project, including open-source libraries and frameworks that could be useful for the final system. Our research was split in to 2 categories which was frontend research and backend research.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Use-cases</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/requirements/2016/11/09/usecases.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Use-cases" /><published>2016-11-09T23:30:51+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-09T23:30:51+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/requirements/2016/11/09/usecases</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/requirements/2016/11/09/usecases.html">&lt;p&gt;This is a list of use cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--  List OverView --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;table-responsive decisionTable&quot;&gt; 
	&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered&quot;&gt;
		&lt;thead&gt;
	      	&lt;tr&gt;
	        	&lt;th&gt;Use case ID&lt;/th&gt;
	        	&lt;th&gt;Use Case Name&lt;/th&gt;
	      	&lt;/tr&gt;
    	&lt;/thead&gt;
    	&lt;tbody&gt;
    		&lt;col width=&quot;20%&quot; /&gt;
  			&lt;col width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;    		
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		       	&lt;td&gt;UC1&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Create Account&lt;/td&gt;		        
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		       	&lt;td&gt;UC2&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Explore information of program &lt;/td&gt;		        
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		       	&lt;td&gt;UC3&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Register for a mentorship program&lt;/td&gt;		        
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		       	&lt;td&gt;UC4&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Setting matching preference&lt;/td&gt;		        
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		       	&lt;td&gt;UC5&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Define user's own interests&lt;/td&gt;		        
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		       	&lt;td&gt;UC6&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Messaging system for mentor and mentee&lt;/td&gt;		        
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		       	&lt;td&gt;UC7&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Check individual profile&lt;/td&gt; 
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		       	&lt;td&gt;UC8&lt;/td&gt;		        
		        &lt;td&gt;Get information about user's mentor or mentee&lt;/td&gt;		        	        
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;/tbody&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered&quot;&gt;  &lt;!-- Usecase1 --&gt;
		&lt;tbody&gt;
			&lt;col width=&quot;20%&quot; /&gt;
  			&lt;col width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;USE CASE&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Create Account&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;ID&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;UC1&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;BREIF DESCRIPTION&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Allow uses to create their own account and set up basic information &lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRIMARY ACTORS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRECONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;None&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;MAIN FLOW&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;
					1.Click 'Create an Account' button.&lt;br /&gt;
					2.Fill the required information in sign up page.&lt;br /&gt;
					3.Click 'Sign up' button
				&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;POSTCONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User account is set up and is redirected to home page&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			
		&lt;/tbody&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered&quot;&gt; &lt;!-- 2 --&gt;
		&lt;tbody&gt;
			&lt;col width=&quot;20%&quot; /&gt;
  			&lt;col width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;USE CASE&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Explore information of specific mentorship program&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;ID&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;UC2&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;BREIF DESCRIPTION&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Users chooses from the listed mentorship programs to find more information about the mentoring program&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRIMARY ACTORS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRECONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User must be registered and is already signed in&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;MAIN FLOW&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;
				1.Go to home page&lt;br /&gt;
				2.Click on the desired mentorship program which are listed.
				&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;POSTCONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User is redirected to a decription page of the specific mentorship program before proceeding to next step.&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			
		&lt;/tbody&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered&quot;&gt; &lt;!-- 3 --&gt;
		&lt;tbody&gt;
			&lt;col width=&quot;20%&quot; /&gt;
  			&lt;col width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;USE CASE&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Register for a mentorship program&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;ID&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;UC3&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;BREIF DESCRIPTION&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User registers for mentorship program of their interest.&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRIMARY ACTORS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRECONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User must be logged in to their account&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;MAIN FLOW&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;
					1.Go to home page&lt;br /&gt;
					2.Click on desired mentorship program&lt;br /&gt;
					3.Click the 'Register Here' button&lt;br /&gt;
					4.Choose the option of signing up as a mentor or mentee &lt;br /&gt;
					5.Click 'Submit' to confirm registration.
				&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;POSTCONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;
					1.Redirected back to home page.&lt;br /&gt;
				&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;ALTERNATIVE FLOW&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;
					User decides to set their preference for matching. Use case ID: UC4.
				&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;/tbody&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered&quot;&gt;
	  &lt;!--  4 --&gt;
		&lt;tbody&gt;
			&lt;col width=&quot;20%&quot; /&gt;
  			&lt;col width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;USE CASE&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Setting matching preference&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;ID&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;UC4&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;BREIF DESCRIPTION&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Users can select their desired preferences which is used for matching&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRIMARY ACTORS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRECONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;
					1.Logged in successfully and have selected a valid mentorship program.
				&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;MAIN FLOW&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;
					1.Clicked 'Find Your Interests' button&lt;br /&gt;
					2.Choose from list of preferences&lt;br /&gt;
					3.Click 'Finish' button to confirm and save preferences.
				&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;POSTCONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User's preferences for matching is saved&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;	
		&lt;/tbody&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered&quot;&gt;  &lt;!-- 5 --&gt;
		&lt;tbody&gt;
			&lt;col width=&quot;20%&quot; /&gt;
  			&lt;col width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;USE CASE&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Define user's own preference&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;ID&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;UC5&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;BREIF DESCRIPTION&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Users define their own preference tags which is not listed.&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRIMARY ACTORS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRECONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Logged in successfully and have selected a valid mentorship program&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;MAIN FLOW&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;
					1.Clicked 'to find your interests' button&lt;br /&gt;
					2.Type in their desired preference in the textbox below&lt;br /&gt;
					3.Click 'Add' button.
				&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;POSTCONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Self-defined preference is saved along with other preferences&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;	
		&lt;/tbody&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered&quot;&gt;  &lt;!-- 6 --&gt;
		&lt;tbody&gt;
			&lt;col width=&quot;20%&quot; /&gt;
  			&lt;col width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;USE CASE&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Messanging system for mentor and mentee&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;ID&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;UC6&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;BREIF DESCRIPTION&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Users get a notification when they receive a message.&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRIMARY ACTORS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRECONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User is registered and logged in successfully&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;MAIN FLOW&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;
					1.Go to home page&lt;br /&gt;
					2.Click the side-bar menu&lt;br /&gt;
					3.Click 'Contact' button
				&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;POSTCONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Users can see any notifications from their mentee or mentor&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;/tbody&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered&quot;&gt;  &lt;!-- 7 --&gt;
		&lt;tbody&gt;
			&lt;col width=&quot;20%&quot; /&gt;
  			&lt;col width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;USE CASE&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Check individual profile&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;ID&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;UC7&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;BREIF DESCRIPTION&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Users could see information about themselves which includes current role and current enrolled programs.&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRIMARY ACTORS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRECONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Logged in successfully&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;MAIN FLOW&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;
					1.Go to home page&lt;br /&gt;
					2.Click the side-bar menu&lt;br /&gt;
					3.Click 'Profile' button.
				&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;POSTCONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Users could see their own profiles along with its details.&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;/tbody&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered&quot;&gt;  &lt;!-- 8 --&gt;
		&lt;tbody&gt;
			&lt;col width=&quot;20%&quot; /&gt;
  			&lt;col width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;USE CASE&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Get information about the user's mentor or mentees&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;ID&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;UC8&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;BREIF DESCRIPTION&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Users can see information about their mentor or mentees&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRIMARY ACTORS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;User&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;PRECONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Logged in successfully &lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;MAIN FLOW&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;
					1.Go to home page&lt;br /&gt;
					2.Click the side-bar menu&lt;br /&gt;
					3.Click 'My mentor' button or 'My mentee' button.
				&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;POSTCONDITIONS&lt;/td&gt;
				&lt;td&gt;Information about their mentors and mentees is displayed.&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;/tbody&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#top&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot;&gt;^ Back to top&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">This is a list of use cases.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MosCoW Requirements</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/requirements/2016/11/07/moscow-requirements.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MosCoW Requirements" /><published>2016-11-07T23:30:51+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-07T23:30:51+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/requirements/2016/11/07/moscow-requirements</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/requirements/2016/11/07/moscow-requirements.html">&lt;p&gt;This is a list of all the requirements as agreed and finalised with our client. These requirements are subject to change over the course of the development phase of this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table-responsive&quot;&gt;
	&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered&quot;&gt;
		&lt;thead&gt;
	      	&lt;tr&gt;
	        	&lt;th&gt;Requirement&lt;/th&gt;
	        	&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
	        	&lt;th&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
	      	&lt;/tr&gt;
    	&lt;/thead&gt;
    	&lt;tbody&gt;
    		&lt;!-- Must Haves --&gt;
    		&lt;tr class=&quot;category-header&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Must Have&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		       	&lt;td&gt;Matching system&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;There must be a matching algorithm that matches mentors and mentees as best as possible according to their preferences.&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Functional&lt;/td&gt;
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		       	&lt;td&gt;Preferences for matching&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;There must be a system for mentors and mentees to specify their preferences for matching, for instance interests.&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Functional&lt;/td&gt;
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Separate mentorship programmes&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;The system must allow for a number of separate mentorship programmes with their own matching constraints.&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Non-Functional&lt;/td&gt;
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Personal status&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Users must be able to see the status of their mentorships, for instance whether they can match with users and how active the mentorship is.&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Functional&lt;/td&gt;
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Web Application&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;The application must be able to be accessed on both mobile and desktop form factors&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Functional&lt;/td&gt;
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;User Interface and Usability&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;The application must operate on a user friendly interface which is simple to use&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Non-Functional&lt;/td&gt;
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;!-- Should Have --&gt;
		    &lt;tr class=&quot;category-header&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Should Have&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		       	&lt;td&gt;Profile system&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Users should be able to create and manage a simple profile so that other users can learn about them. Should include name, image and perhaps a short bio.&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Functional&lt;/td&gt;
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		       	&lt;td&gt;Notifications&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Users should be able to receive notifications about key features of the app, for instance when matches are allocated. Should also work across different form factors&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Functional&lt;/td&gt;
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Admin bulk operation interface&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;There should be an interface that allows admins to perform bulk create/read/update/destroy (CRUD) operatons easily.&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Functional&lt;/td&gt;
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;!-- Could Have --&gt;
		    &lt;tr class=&quot;category-header&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Could Have&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Mentorship meeting record&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;The app could be able to store records of the mentor and mentee meeting each other during the course of the mentorship, with the ability to add comments to this.&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Functional&lt;/td&gt;
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Instant messaging&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;The app could be able to store records of the mentor and mentee meeting each other during the course of the mentorship, with the ability to add comments to this.&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Functional&lt;/td&gt;
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;tr&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Notifications to meet&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;The app could facilitate instant messaging betweenmentors and mentees.&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Functional&lt;/td&gt;
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		    &lt;!-- Would Have --&gt;
		    &lt;tr class=&quot;category-header&quot;&gt;&lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;Would Have&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
		     &lt;tr&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Corporate Directory Lookup&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;The app would be able to use the company’s internal “Corporate Directory” to populate users’ profiles&lt;/td&gt;
		        &lt;td&gt;Functional&lt;/td&gt;
		    &lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;/tbody&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><summary type="html">This is a list of all the requirements as agreed and finalised with our client. These requirements are subject to change over the course of the development phase of this project.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Background Research</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/11/04/background-research.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Background Research" /><published>2016-11-04T23:30:51+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-04T23:30:51+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/11/04/background-research</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/group19/development/2016/11/04/background-research.html">&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot;&gt;Overcoming the Stable Marriage Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After researching online regarding solutions to the Stable Marriage Problem, we found that applying the &lt;strong&gt;Gale-Shapley Algorithm&lt;/strong&gt; would be an effective way to find a stable match between mentors and mentees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gale-Shapley Algorithm involves a number of iterations or “rounds” where mentees are able to choose a fixed number of prefered mentors ordered by rank. Then the system will match mentors and mentees based on how suitable the match is between a mentor and mentee. By using this algortihm, we can ensure that every mentees gets matched with a mentor and no one is unpaired. A more detailed design of thhe matching process is available at the Architecture Research and Design section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-header&quot;&gt;Existing Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We searched for some existing applications that does matching between individuals as part of the initial stages of research. This helped us gain a basic idea of some features that we may like to include in our final product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Mentor Match&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mentormatch.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mentor Match&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an existing open source website that had a very similar concept to what our client was trying to acheive. Mentor Match is open to everyone and allows individuals with experience in a particular skillset to act as mentors to help mentees improve on that particular skillset.
Since this website is open to everyone, it makes exchange of knowledge very simple as anyone could take part in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are certain features that the website lacks in terms of security as there is no verification as there is no way to assure that users applying to be a mentor has the skillset to become one. Also there were different types of mentor schemes requested by our client which differ with the schemes provided on the Mentor Match website. Despite the differences in structure of this website with the web application we are about to build, Mentor Match could be a useful guideline on the basic foundation of our web application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Business Mentoring&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.management-mentors.com/products/corporate-mentoring-products-overview&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Mentoring&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; matches based on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus areas/ competencies: There system have 25 default competencies to choose. (useful)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forced choice questions:Provide questions that have several answers to select. Make the preferences of matching more specific. (useful)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Personality test:(optional)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ranking of key roles: In this section, mentorees must decide what type of mentor they want based on how they order the following roles: teacher, sponsor, cheerleader, counselor, and friend (meaning if they put “cheerleader” first and “counselor” last, it’s more important that the mentor is a cheerleader than a friend). Mentors must decide the type of mentor they want to be and do the same thing, ranking the roles in order of most important to least. (useful)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Essay section (not useful)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also provide system matching:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Auto matching: makes matches based on algorithm without any review.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;three-steps-matching (also combines human touch, not 100% system matching):
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Program manager choose 3 tentative mentors for individual mentee.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Comparing mentoring forms(inforamtion) of the mentee with each mentor&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The program manager makes the final choice&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we could learn from this project:
As the result of precise matching algorithm,this application has high percentage of successful matching (90% according to its website). From my research, the division of focus areas and ranking of key roles play an important role in matching, thats what we could follow in our app, give a list of skills as tags for user to choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lead sub-header&quot;&gt;Dating Applications&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Dating applications may not be the most professional apps to be used in a workplace, however the concept of these types of application is very similar to what was requested by our client. Our Client even quoted that this application “could be considered a kind of dating app”. Most dating applications have simple and elegent user interfaces that users can act easily with. This could be applied to our application so that employees in Atos workplace can use our application with ease. Concepts such as user profiles, notifications, instant messaging could be included in our application which already exist in dating applications.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Overcoming the Stable Marriage Problem
After researching online regarding solutions to the Stable Marriage Problem, we found that applying the Gale-Shapley Algorithm would be an effective way to find a stable match between mentors and mentees.

The Gale-Shapley Algorithm involves a number of iterations or “rounds” where mentees are able to choose a fixed number of prefered mentors ordered by rank. Then the system will match mentors and mentees based on how suitable the match is between a mentor and mentee. By using this algortihm, we can ensure that every mentees gets matched with a mentor and no one is unpaired. A more detailed design of thhe matching process is available at the Architecture Research and Design section.</summary></entry></feed>
